[Music]
good evening good day everybody welcome
to the 67th live episode of ask abhijit
and thank you all for being here you
know it's a privilege to get even five
seconds of someone's attention
and i am getting so much of all of your
attention it's i'm truly blessed thank
you so much thank you so much for being
here and asking me all the questions
i am getting literally thousands of
questions per week
so please don't hate me if i can't pick
your question what i'm trying to do is
i'm trying to pick up a wide range of
questions that will
be informative hopefully to everybody
over a long period of time so that's
what i'm trying to do so if i don't pick
your question do not be discouraged do
not be disappointed
uh it's possible i may have already
answered the question in the past uh i
see many people asking me questions that
i have answered in the past i have lots
of short clips on this channel please go
to the search button on my channel and
search for whatever question you have
quite likely i mean i must have answered
over a thousand questions by now
it's likely that i may already have
answered your question so look there
and otherwise keep asking your questions
and i will try and pick as many as
possible
so today as you know i am going to
answer questions that i have picked from
the uh comments that you have uh the
questions you have asked in the comments
and i'll hopefully answer about 30 or so
questions so let us get going right away
into
your questions
right question one
this is by venue
why
[Laughter]
why have all eminent strategic affairs
experts rebranded themselves as
geopolitical analysts after your first
podcast april 2021 with ranvadia
the word geopolitics did not exist
anywhere in indian discourse beyond
before your april podcast
i think everyone is listening to your
podcast listening to your podcasts and
quietly learning you're very influential
you know um
you we should all learn from each other
i'm not sure about what you're saying
but
i do remember in the recent past that
all uh
all these experts were called strategic
affairs experts for sure yes and
recently it does seem to be that
they are now all called geopolitical
analysts and experts i'm not sure if
it's a consequence of what of the
podcast i did with ranveer and the other
podcast i have done on my own channel
over here
but in case it is so then great i have
no objection to that everybody should
learn from each other
and
if you're watching hello hi everybody
what else can i say great i i'm very
happy about it
okay question two it's by dimitri
currently the indian air force lacks
strategic bombers despite being the
fourth largest air force and the top
three air forces in the world have
strategic bombers for several decades my
question is does india need any kind of
strategic bombers okay so the question
is interesting
so the first thing is what is a
strategic bomber a strategic bomber is a
large aircraft that has a range of at
least five thousand kilometers and it
the range can extend up to fifteen
thousand or more kilometers so it's a
medium to long range aircraft minimum
five thousand kilometers i would say
and it it should be able to carry at
least 10 000 kilos of explosives of
bombs that it can drop so that's what we
mean by a strategic bomber the americans
have a number of strategic bombers the
russians have been developing and using
strategic bombers for a long time the
chinese have at least one strategic
bomber and they are developing at least
one more
if you are part of the the stealth
bomber that the americans have that's a
strategic bomber it's go it's a long
distance long endurance aircraft so
three countries
have the this capability the us the
russians and the chinese
and the question is does india need
any kind of strategic bombers it all
depends why does a country need
strategic bombers when it has a large
area of geopolitical interest when it
wants to project power over a large a
geographical area that's when you need
strategic bombers so that you can
potentially possibly if required go and
bomb someone far away
right so what kind of country needs this
a country there is a great power
small powers regional powers medium
powers don't really need strategic
bombers because their area of
geopolitical influence typically doesn't
extend very far beyond their
geographical beyond their political
borders
but a country that is a superpower a
great power or an aspiring great power
needs strategic bombers in order to give
itself more options
military options because the military
option is an important in in fact a
vital component of a nation's hard power
so
does india need strategic bombers well
the question is does india want to be a
great power
if india does aspire to be a great power
a superpower then at some point in time
in the near future india should acquire
or
build
strategic bombers if india is content to
be a small power or a regional power
then india doesn't need strategic
bombers what india does right now is it
it employs multi-role fighter aircraft
as bombers for instance the jaguar the
sukhoi
various mig aircraft these are currently
and also the rafale aircraft so these
are multi-purpose aircraft with a
significant load carrying capacity these
are fighter aircraft okay
and these are the aircraft that india
uses for bombing purposes
we cannot
do this
very far beyond our geographical beyond
our political borders because these
aircraft they don't have 5000 or more
kilometer range
the sukhoi has a good range
and it can launch missiles and such but
it cannot launch 10 000 plus kilograms
of bombs right that sort of thing
so as of today india is a regional power
at best because it doesn't have the
capability to
do what
strategic bombers can do we do have
missiles and all that but those are for
other purposes those are for deterrence
purposes mainly
so if in the the answer is simple if
india aspires to be a great power a
superpower then it definitely will need
strategic bombers we will either have to
acquire it from another country or build
our own
so that's the two options we have but i
i would say that india should aspire to
be a great power a superpower
and therefore india should
acquire strategic bombers
dimitri again
russia is pitching its sukhoi 75 fighter
jet to india and to other countries
chances are that it will also compete in
the for the 114
uh
medium role
multi-role fighter jet aircraft program
but considering the price and technology
they're claiming to offer it's is it
really stealthy and a good fighter
aircraft and do you see chances of india
purchasing it so i haven't examined the
sukhoi 75 in great detail it seems to
have a certain amount a certain level of
stealth capabilities it's not a proper
stealth aircraft it's not invisible to
radar but it does have a smaller cross
section than the sukhoi 30 or the sukhoi
those families of aircraft so it does it
it is
in some senses
uh to some extent a stealth aircraft
it's they're saying it's a fourth or
fifth generation i think most likely a
fourth generation aircraft maybe fifth
i'm not sure but it's not a complete
stealth aircraft the technology i'm sure
the sukhoi uh
aircraft family is excellent no doubt
about that
uh so should india
acquire this aircraft it depends we need
to evaluate the aircraft i think it's a
single
engine is it a single engine aircraft
most likely a single-engine aircraft and
most likely a single seater single pilot
aircraft does india need that or do we
need double engine double pi two pilot
aircrafts that is something the air
force has to decide most likely we would
need an aircraft that has
which has a greater
uh an aircraft which would have two
engines and maybe a two-seater because
that allows the pilots to uh share their
responsibilities
so uh
the the sukhoi family is is a great
family of aircraft no doubt about that
but does this specific aircraft fit
india's requirements and the bigger
question is should we keep on buying
uh military hardware from other
countries or should we develop our own
hardware should we develop our own
fighter aircraft i think it is always
best to have your own
indigenous technology your indigenous
aircraft so india is developing a newer
variant of the lca pages aircraft right
a
better variant of the pages india is
developing most likely hopefully a twin
engine deck based fighter which will
operate from aircraft carriers india is
developing the amca the fifth gen the
fourth generation aircraft or fighter
aircraft which will have multiple roles
and it will have elements of stealth as
well
so
i think india should concentrate and
focus all its energies and resources on
those programs hopefully in the next 10
years we will have these aircraft flying
for our
air force
so in the meanwhile
if there is a gap if there is a gap in
capabilities if there is a gap in the
number of aircraft we need to have we
would like to have then as a stop-gap
measure we can acquire a number of
aircraft from abroad we are acquiring
some rafale aircraft 36 or maybe more
later
uh
i've heard that we may be acquiring a
few more sukhoi 30 aircraft sukhoi 30
mki aircraft
so that may work for for a time for for
the time being
and maybe we will still go ahead with
these with this requirement for 114
multi-role fighter aircraft we will see
so as a stop gap measure we can
certainly consider foreign aircraft but
in the long run
we must develop our own aircraft
okay utkar says what are the main
beliefs of the charvakas and are you a
charvaka the charvaka philosophy is one
of the one of the philosophies that
comes under the dharmic umbrella
so in the dharmic world there are a
whole there's a whole range of
philosophical schools of thought
charvaka yoga mansa
sankhya
vedanta
and so on and so forth i think there are
at least nine major schools of thought
and lots of other
schools of thought as well so charvaka
is one of these
dharmic
well it it does fall under the darwik
umbrella what are the main beliefs
charvaka is pure materialism according
to the charvaka philosophy
all that exists is what you can see and
what you can observe
and there is nothing beyond that there
is no karma there is no soul there are
no gods there is nothing apart from that
so the only objective only purpose of
life is to enjoy your existence enjoy
your material senses enjoy the material
world and that's it there is nothing
beyond that so that is in brief the
belief of the charvakas
am i charvaka absolutely not i am not a
charvaka
considering you are from a scientific
background do you identify yourself as
an atheist or a dharmic person do
science and dharma defy each other
do science and dharma defy each other
well you know all of india's ancient
scientists were rishis
they all came under they all adhered to
one of the major schools of dharmic
thought the
one of the major schools philosophical
schools schools of philosophical dharmic
thought
and philosophy is not spirituality it is
not blind beliefs
philosophy involves logic philosophy
doesn't exist without logic but
philosophy also
encompasses uh
thoughts and ideas and things like that
that may be exist beyond the observable
or physical realm so that is what
philosophy is in every single indian
scientist mathematician astronomer etc
was an adherent of one of the major
philosophical schools of thought and
none of them were charvaka for ins for
example
so in dharma
there has been science always dharma has
never said that believe something
blindly the world is flat and that's it
and don't go beyond that no
people haven't been burned at the stake
for for saying new things for coming up
with new ideas
india has contributed the most in the
ancient world to science
astronomy
uh pharmacology toxicology ayurveda
yoga
mathematics
in finite series calculus
uh trigonometry algebra all of that came
from india and all of the mathematicians
all of the scientists they were all
racist dharmic rishis so science and
dharma do not defy each other dharma is
very very scientific
if india's universities had not been
destroyed a thousand years ago india
would have been at the extreme forefront
of science and technology today because
that's what india always was
india indians would have discovered
relativity quantum mechanics they may
even have been able to reconcile gravity
and
and and quantum theory you know
so science and dharma do not defy each
other now when you talk about atheist
you're most likely talking about
charvakas well if you look at india's
great philosophers india's great
scientists astronomers brahma gupta arya
but
neela kanta and so many more none of
them were charvaka none of them were
atheists
and i also do not identify myself as an
atheist
looks like a sanskrit name but wikipedia
says it's a sogdian language word what's
your take
so let's uh
let's go to our our map the map is our
best friend
all right we have a map here where is
samar
all right
so let's go further so samarkand is over
here
it's north of india
yeah if you go way south of india you
come into pa i mean if you go south due
south of samarkand you reach pakistan
which was historically always for
thousands of years india so samarkand is
not far from india as such it is in the
region known as
known in ancient times as sagdia
and the language they spoke there was
the sagdian language which is very close
to the gandharan language the gandhari
language today it is classified by
western linguists as an iranian language
they try to classify everything into
iranian into the iranian language family
anyhow
so samarkand was
is here it is part it is located in
ancient sagdia
and there is this other city here called
tashkent both of these cities are in
uzbekistan
uzbekistan right
now the question is
samarkand sounds like a sanskrit name
wikipedia says it's a sogden language
word well wikipedia is not a reliable
source of information have you heard of
taksha sheela taksha sheela is down
south in present-day pakistan
it was one of our great great ancient
universities maybe the oldest known
university in the entire universe
known universe
so there was taksha sheela
it is believed that tashkent the
original name was takshakhand
and samarkand's original name was samar
khand
but the western linguist and western
historians do not accept this
but hey we don't have to accept that
nonsense either
so it is well known
that in before the turkic invasions the
entirety of central asia was very much
a part of greater india
buddhism was rampant everywhere it was
spread everywhere not only buddhism
hinduism as well you had hindu temples
all the way
west in armenia
in armenia azerbaijan etc so hinduism
and buddhism which is the same thing was
spread dharmic culture essentially was
spread all across central asia so it is
not inconceivable that tashkent would
have actually been called takshakhand in
the past and samarkand may have been
called samarkand in the past and in fact
even parts of a present-day northern
china kashgar for instance
you see the city of kashgar here it's a
small town over here it was known until
quite recently as kashinagar
right
so that is the history that is the truth
and uh so it's it's quite possible that
samarkand and tashkent were known as
samarkand and
in the past
okay
next question
sagar says please explain about the
chandra shekhar limit and schwarzschild
radius can we create a miniature black
hole from any small mass say a brick or
a molecule good question so what is the
chandra shaker limit the chandra shekhar
limit is the maximum
mass of a stable white dwarf star a
white dwarf is something that's left
behind essentially from the death of a
large star and the chandra shekhar limit
is the minimum maximum sorry maximum
mass that a stable white dwarf can have
if the mass goes beyond that then it
it either turns into a neutron star or a
black hole so the chandrasekhar limit is
most uh
uh it's it is measured to be
approximately 1.44
solar masses so 1.44 multiplied by the
mass of the sun that is the
chandrasekhar limit
and this was discovered by the indian
astrophysicist subramanyam chandrasekhar
in the 1930s when he was still a
graduate student right so he
discovered this he did the calculations
he published the papers and there was a
big controversy because there was this
so-called eminent
uh
astrophysicist called arthur eddington
he was british he opposed this and he
was very imminent he had a very big
reputation and all so people just
quietly accepted what he said and that
was a so that kind of hindered
chandrashekar's work for a very long
time arthur eddington he claimed that
there should be a law of nature to
prevent a star from behaving in this
absurd
how stupid this is when dogma comes in
the way of science and it's unfortunate
this that you see this very often among
eminent
scientists anyhow so that's what the
chandrasekhar limit is
what is the schwarzschild radius it is
uh the
radius of the event horizon of a
non-rotating schwarzschild black hole a
non-rotating black hole is called a
schwarzschild black hole and its radius
the radius of its event horizon the
the
boundary of the
the point at which even light cannot go
back that is called the hostile radius
it is its calculation is i mean its
formula is very simple 2 mg by c squared
where m is the mass of the black hole g
is newton's gravitational constant and c
is the speed of light 2 mg by c squared
that is the schwarzschild radius of any
black hole the sun
has a schwarzschild radius of
approximately 3 kilometers the earth
has a short shell radius of
approximately nine millimeters
and the moon has a schwarzschild radius
of approximately 0.1
millimeters so if you compress the
entire mass of the sun
into a radius of three kilometers then
it will become a black hole
if you compress the earth the entire
mass of the earth in a radius
of approximately nine millimeters
then it will become a black hole and if
you take the entire moon and you squeeze
it into a radius
of 0.1 millimeters that's when it will
also become a black hole so you can
create a miniature black hole from any
mass as long as you are able to compress
it into its schwarzschild radius whether
it's a brick whether it's a molecule
whether it's the earth the sun anything
every mass
has a schwarzschild radius of
calculation is very simple 2 mg by c
squared
so that's your answer sir
next question
okay these i get a number of questions
like these so i've taken two pratik says
why is the british saint george cross
still a part of the naval flag kuldip
asks and says i think it's high time we
design our own army navy air force flags
we are still using a copy-paste version
of the colonial british flags please
share your views about this
all right so what is the
the controversy about let me share my
screen
okay
one second let me
here we are
so this is the saint george's cross this
is what it what it looks like it is this
this is the cross right
this is essentially the uh
the flag of england it's also part of
the union jack the flag of great britain
so-called great britain
now what is the indian
navy
flag
well here's the indian naval flag
it has the saint george cross with some
local stuff added to it but the main
component is the saint george cross
there you have it
there you have it and so on and so forth
so the question is
why
why are we still continuing with this
colonial
uh representation in our armed forces
why does the army navy the navy
essentially i'm not sure about the army
but the navy certainly has
this
saint george cross as as the major
component of its flag and that's a valid
question
we
are supposed to have
been independent for over seven decades
why are we still worshiping the symbols
of colonialism oppression
and all that why are we still doing that
why can't we have a naval flag that is
entirely indian
why can't we have why can't we
decolonize ourselves of all these
various
symbols
of the of the millennium of humiliation
the symbols of occupation the symbols of
plunder of the destruction of indian
civilization why do we need to
still carry on these flags and the
answer is very simple our armed forces
are deeply colonized this is not a
criticism of the armed forces by the way
our soldiers are the bravest soldiers in
the world they are the best soldiers in
the world our generals our leaders are
great
no doubt about that and yet we are
maintaining
we are continuing colonial traditions
somebody at the
pointed out i saw some comment that the
armed forces are extensively anglicized
and uh even if you read vs nypal
one of his books i don't remember which
one i've read a few so in one of his
books about india he says he spoke about
visiting
an indian army camp and
way after india's
so-called independence
and he noticed a portrait of the queen
of england in in the dinner hall dining
hall
in the indian army long after
independence so this is unfortunately a
continuation of the colonial traditions
of the indian army
all the
many or most of the traditions are
colonial traditions
and you also see things like we still
retain the names of the regiments that
the british gave us
the rajputana rifles maratha whatever
uh sikh regiment
uh assam rifles
these
are essentially names they gave to our
regiments based on their so-called uh
what was it called martial race theory
they
they said they they claimed that india
is home to a number of martial races the
juts the rajputs the six the marathas
and some other people
and they gave regiments the names of
these these so-called ethnicities or
races right
what this does is that it creates
this this divide even even among the
army the gurkha regiment is another one
right it's another ethnic name
we should not
name our regiments after ethnicities or
or states or regions
this creates an unnecessary divide in
the army if you look at julius caesar
during the roman times his regiments
were all numbered they were given
numbers
if you look at the americans i think the
u.s army also has numbered regiments
by giving names what will happen is that
tomorrow the gujaratis will say we want
a gujarati regiment the manipuris will
say we want a manipura regiment the
udiyas will say we want the odia
regiment the tamils will say why isn't
there a tamil regiment and so on and so
forth this is unnecessary so there is so
much
colonial baggage the armed forces are
still carrying on i think the great
general
bipin singh ravath was trying to reform
the army it was his great task
unfortunately his life was cut short and
i hope that whoever is appointed the new
cds will take these reforms forward
because india's armed forces need
significant
and deep reforms so yes these questions
are
very valid
they have to be taken seriously we
cannot have colonized armed forces you
see that after the great general
robert died
many people
ex-armed forces service people service
men they went on social media and
celebrated the death of this man
india's chief of defense
uh staff right cds
it makes me ask the question
why why is it so why do certain sections
of india's armed forces
have such sentiments because when you
are celebrating the death of your top
general
it is some it is an event that is
detrimental to the national interest so
you are celebrating harm to india and to
india's national interest and that sort
of sentiment is unacceptable in the
armed forces so i am not saying the
present serving uh
personnel have such sentiments but
certainly the people who have retired
who were part of the nehruvian and post
neruvian regimes
certainly seem to have a certain
level of that sentiment some of them at
least seem to have it so india's armed
forces need to be
reformed no doubt about it there is no
question about their professionalism
their abilities their capabilities they
are the best in the world they are the
bravest people they are you cannot
question their integrity but there seems
to be
some element of colonialism left over
that needs to be addressed and addressed
soon so i hope that the
that the person who is appointed the
next cds will carry on the flame of
general ravath and complete the reforms
that he was undertaking
all right two questions again one by
swarup and one by science soldier
at least one thousand years before
pythagoras bodhiana mentioned the
geometric theory of three-sided triangle
the credit the credit for authoring the
earliest
sutras goes to him why wasn't it
acknowledged and did not receive any
kind of credit or credit or recognition
bodhiani is said to be the original
mathematician behind this so-called
pythagoras theorem indians discovered it
at least a thousand years before the
before pythagoras was born can you
confirm this
so if you look at western mathematician
western historians of science they claim
that bodhiani lived maybe 100 200 years
before pythagoras that's what they claim
now the sulba sutras are part of the
vedic corpus of texts these are vedic
texts and the vedic era was way before
pythagoras
way before all that right
so the what the claim doesn't make any
sense it is completely incorrect and it
should be
brushed off it should be laughed off so
it is clear that bodhiana lived a long
time before pythagoras we don't know
we're not quite sure when and that's the
main problem in indian historiography
indian history we don't know the
the dates of the deep antiquity of india
but clearly bodhiana the great rishi
bodhiana lived long before pythagoras
and yes
the the the so-called pythagorean
theorem was well known to him he
published it he wrote about it in the
sulbasutras
right
and if you look at wikipedia i think
they they call it bodhiana knew about
the pythagorean theorem before
pythagoras pythagoras was born so this
is a symptom one of the many many
symptoms of the
utter eurocentricity of history
and the
this this
this state exists because india's
historians
are
blind followers of the west they have no
original ideas
they are incapable of doing any genuine
original authentic research of their own
and they are too scared to assert the
truth
and many of them are just
sold out
most of them are sold out the the
eminent official mainstream historians
of india so it is clear that the
so-called pythagoras theorem should be
called the bodhiana theorem so let's all
decide to call it that way right
all right next question
is it true that in 1941 stalin
ordered to open the tomb of timur the
monster and what did they find in his
tomb you know what they found they found
the bones of a monster
yes so it is true i don't know which
year it was but stalin did order the
examination of uh timur's tomb they went
into timur's mausoleum they opened his
tomb they pulled a skeleton out and they
did all kinds of tests on the guy so
let's take a look at what this was like
let's take a look at mr timur the
monster
all right let's get away from the map go
to
google.com
and the
tim moore exumation
let's see let's go to images
so this is
when they
examined his
dead body his skeleton
this is a larger image of that
this is a picture of the guy's head the
great monster's head
the skull
let's see some other images here it is
again
and here is a reconstruction of his face
based on the body on the skull
uh here is another
image of his skeleton
so yeah so so his body was exhumed
and they reconstructed his face from his
skull this is what his face looked like
so this is a reasonably accurate
representation of what timor the monster
timur the lame would actually have
looked like like in real life in old age
and they also discovered that he was
indeed lame so he did have some
deformity or or
injury
in one of his
legs
which is why he was called
or timur the lame
so that's what they that's what actually
happened and that's what they found in
his tomb they dismantled his skeleton
took it out did all kinds of studies
reconstructed his face based on the
skull and then eventually they placed
the bones back in the tomb and closed it
again and that's why people today even
today go to
to see his tomb some people want to go
and play tribute pay tribute to him and
some people want to go and dance at his
tomb so
all right
next question
it's by goku
is the great game still going on is
india the last still the last remaining
prize
if the great game is still going on how
much wealth and resources they want to
suck out of india aren't they satisfied
with what they did over
to for over 200 years
well what you're referring to the great
game well what was the original great
game it was the
it was the uh
it was the struggle to capture
and control central asia
it was between the british empire
and the russian empire the british
controlled india
and they wanted to control central asia
as well so that the russians could not
come down come south and try to
invade india and take over parts of
india as well the russians knew that
india was an extraordinarily rich land
that the british were
profiting from they were pillaging
plundering the land and that's how they
became incredibly rich and powerful and
the russians wanted some of that so they
also wanted to invade india and colonize
india
and the key to that was central asia so
that was the great game the uh
the struggle the battle for control of
central asia so that was in the 19th
century it all essentially ended with
the crimean war in the middle of the
19th century when in which the russians
lost
but there was some some of it still
continued until later
tibbett was also in involved in this to
some extent and so on and so forth so
that was the great game
and the prize the big prize was india
so the question is is the great game
still going on the great game is always
going on india is still
a big prize
there's a reason why the west doesn't
want india to industrialize and become a
manufacturing and
uh technological superpower india
see if you become a manufacturer in
superpower you your gdp shoots up
it shoots up we have seen that in the
case of china in 30 years the gdp shot
up and
in a way
went way bus pass india it is now almost
a middle income country today all
because of manufacturing so if india
becomes manufacturing powerhouse a
technological powerhouse rnd powerhouse
scientific powerhouse then it will
become a superpower it is guaranteed
what the west wants
is they want india
to remain a large market of consumers
not producers if you produce you grow
your gdp grows if you consume you are a
huge market to which they can sell all
their junk
fast food
social media
and so on and so forth
if you go and eat it eat
go to your favorite pizza chain go to
your favorite burger chain go to your
favorite fast food chain
it's quite likely that it's it has some
element of american
investment or maybe it's an american
owned
chain or brand
so they want india
to remain a huge market that doesn't
produce anything but buys things from
elsewhere consumes things from from the
west essentially
and that is what they want because that
will enrich them it will keep on
enriching them at the cost of india
india's resources will keep flowing out
the same way they kept flowing out
during the east india company days and
the british raj days
so this is called neo-colonial
this is a new form of colonialism
and as long as india remains
under industrialized
india will be
at their mercy and that's why india
needs to become a manufacturing and
industrial powerhouse
if we do that we become a superpower
economically at least and then it's
about political will whether we become a
military superpower as well or not
so that yes it is definitely true that
india is the last remaining prize the
chinese market is off limits the chinese
are very clear about what their
aims and objectives are they will not
allow their population their citizens to
be used as a market for western garbage
so the big prize 1.3 billion
humans is india that's why they do not
want india to industrialize they want
india to remain a captive market a
nation of consumers not creators
consumers not producers so go ahead
and create go ahead and produce
that is the lesson from this
many of you in the next 10 20 years are
going to lead india and the world in
various domains
in the creative field in the industrial
field in technology in science in
leadership in politics so learn this
lesson heed this lesson india has to
become a manufacturing and technological
and scientific superpower if it wants to
become an overall geopolitical
superpower
okay this is an interesting question
it's by um
did neheru lie in parliament that india
was never offered a u.n
permanent
seat
very uh good question
so
let me share my screen with you and
and offer some
kind of
evidence
all right
so was mr nehru
did mr nehru lie in parliament about the
u.n security council
so uh this is
a very famous article by the wilson
center it says the title is not at the
cost of china india and the un security
council 1950. so there was an offer made
to mr nehru by the us
in 1950 for a permanent seat on the u.n
security council but mr nehru rejected
that he said not at the cost of china he
wanted china to become a permanent
member first and then let's see about
india right so this is what is mentioned
here it is laid out in great detail
now there is this other
article
over here
in the washington post
let us wait for it to load
so if you see down here
all right
it says india was offered a permanent
seat on the secure u.n security council
55 years ago in 1955 but that offer made
by the us and the soviet union was
declined by india's first prime minister
jawaharlal nehru nehru said the seat
should be given to china instead so the
wilson center article talks about 1950
this
washington post article talks about
1955.
isn't that interesting
so 1950 and 1955 the u.s and the ussr
both now take a look at this
this is a statement made by
the former
u.n under secretary general shashi
tharur
mr tharu says
that jawaharlal nehru declined a
u.s offer to india to take the permanent
seat on the u.n security council in 1950
around 1953 and suggested it should be
gone given to china
and he has written this in a book the
invention of india
okay
so mr through has also corroborated this
i think the former president of
mukherjee also corroborated the fact
that india was offered this and mr nehru
declined the offer
now
let's take a look at this all right this
is all on the record i am not making
anything up take a look at this
this is
from
september 28 1955.
okay this is the the proceedings of the
parliament of india
mr nehru
clarifies
in parliament
prime minister nehru has categorically
denied any offer former former or
informal having been received about a
seat for india in the un security
council he made this statement in reply
to a short notice question in the lok
sabha on september 27 1955
by whoever whether india had refused a
seat informally offered to her in the
security council the prime minister
nehru said there has been no offer
formal or informal of this kind some
vague references have appeared in the
press
about it and so on
uh
yeah so so that's what mr nehru said in
parliament now it has already been
clearly established by the evidence from
the wilson center from the washington
post from mr shashi to himself a great
lover of mr nehru and also from
president mukherjee that these offers
were indeed made between 1950 1953 in
1955 and yet it is on the record that mr
nehru denied this officially
in on the floor of the lok sabha in
india's parliament so i will leave it to
you my dear viewers
to judge
whether mr nehru lied in parliament or
not
ujjwal chauhan says does the bloodline
of pandavas still exist
and if it exists then in today's world
who are their descendants
good question so the pandavas were five
in number five brothers right and they
all had multiple children
uh with draupadi with other wives as
well
some of the children died during the
mahabharat of the war abhimanyu died
arjun's son
some others also died but clearly
many of the descendants survived past
the mahabharata war by past the events
of this great war
abhimanyu's son parikshit became the
next emperor the next king of the kuru
region
of the kuru empire
he was the successor of his grand uncle
yudhisthira right
so uh abdi manyu's son became the next
king and his descendants janmajay etc
were the
later kings
of this dynasty and they all had
children so it's clear that their
lineage
survived and proliferated down the line
so the question is so the the bloodline
certainly survived they had many
descendants and when you have many
descendants it's almost a given 99.999
that your bloodline survived and it most
likely
still exists today the question is who
are their descendants now that's a good
question so let me uh
let me uh share an image
to illustrate
who their descendants
might be right
so this is
let me remove the question so you can
see clearly
so let's take a look at how ancestry
works
right we all believe that we are
descendants of one lineage
one single lineage right so let's say
you are in generation zero
if you can see uh
if you can see the top there is
generation zero
and
it is about you you are generation zero
now if you go back 25 years
we assume that one generation is about
25 years so if you go back 25 years your
ancestors are your two parents so you
have two ancestors if you go back 50
years you have four ancestors
uh which who were your grandparents
if you go back 75 years you had eight
ancestors if you go back 100 years you
had 16 ancestors if you go back 500
years you had a million ancestors
so you if you if you go back just five
centuries in your own lineage you had a
million ancestors
a million lines of descent if you go
back 600 years it's 10 million if you go
back 675 million years it's 100 million
so what does this tell us my friends
it tells us that if you go back several
centuries almost everybody who lived in
india at that time was your ancestors
and there will be a lot of
cross-references and all which means
that you won't actually have 10 million
ancestors many of them will be ancestors
of some other lineages so the number of
ancestors will be less
but almost everybody in india is related
to each other
if you look at it in this manner you
don't have a single line of descent you
don't belong to a single family you
belong to you are a descendant of
millions of families and millions of
lineages
now it is known that during the indus
valley time during the
the saraswati civilization india's
population was at least 5 or 10 million
people which was enormous
for that time
right so it indicates and and assuming
that though that was the entire
population of india it indicates that
almost all of those people are your
ancestors and most likely the
mahabharata happened around this time or
maybe slightly before this
and that would indicate that any person
who was alive at that time
anybody at all
would have descendants living today
or relatives living today
and since there were so many descendants
of pandavas
it tells you my friends
that you are all in some way or the
other descended from the pandavas and so
am i
it tells you my friends that all of you
no matter what so-called caste you
belong to no matter what community you
belong to whether you're north east
south west whatever part of india you
all are descended from kings and queens
and emperors of india
that's the answer
vishal says is there any enmity between
the turks and arabs or are they friends
that's an interesting question because
we all see
we all consider
we all believe
that all the nations in the islamic
world are all allies in the work
together right
and yet you will find that there are
lots of schisms and
and enmities and
adversarial relationships
in the islamic world for instance iran
is opposed is an adversary a mortal
adversary of the saudis
and various other other countries
the turks and the iranians don't get
along the turks and the saudis also
don't quite get along and the reason is
very simple the battle for supremacy the
battle for the leadership position the
pole position in the islamic world who
is going to be the leader
the global leader of the islamic ummah
the saudis claim that position because
they are the custodians of the two
holiest
sites of the islamic world mecca and
medina
so they are the custodians of these
sites and that's why they should be the
and also because the islamic religion
came out of arabia right so the saudis
claim to be the natural inheritors of
that leadership title the turks disagree
the turks said that we were the greatest
of the the greatest empire of the
islamic world the ottoman empire the
great conqueror right pati
they conquered
eastern rome they conquered the eastern
roman empire constantinople and made
that made that city their their capital
and they conquered a vast empire across
asia and across parts of europe as well
and theirs was the last caliph of the
islamic world so the turks
claim the turks feel in their blood that
they are the inheritors of the mantle of
the leaders of the islamic world and the
new uh the the latest the the current
leader of turkey mr erdogan
i believe he wishes to be the next
caliph he wants to resuscitate
the ottoman empire
and if you have such ambitions such
geopolitical ambitions then you will
never
envisage or never uh
contemplate the possibility of anybody
else trying to rise to the position and
that's why there is a significant
rivalry between the turks and the arabs
especially the saudis
so
the answer is there is a significant
amount of enmity
at least at a certain level
not outward enmity but clearly
concealed wheeled enmity between the
turks and the arabs
next question is by taher
why didn't the french succeed in india
as their commanding officer in india
dubli was the founder of the divide and
ruled concept
while the british copied them later but
the difference was the british landed in
bengal where the french established
their control in southern india
excellent question
so i will answer this at a conceptual
level not on a detailed historical
chronological level
uh you are right the british
landed in bengal that's why bengal is
the most colonized part of india today
uh the french established the control in
southern india
correct
now what happened
duplay was a very good governor general
he fought the british he tried to
establish
a great
amount of french rule extensive french
rule in india that was the ambition that
was the objective
now it is clear that in the carnatic
wars if the british came out on top the
french lost and after that the french
were never never able to gain much
ground and the british eventually were
able to succeed in um annexing
and and uh
subjugating occupying
the whole of india so why was this why
did the british succeed while the french
failed
you know what they say
they say follow the logistics follow the
money
in any operation in any endeavor in any
project follow the logistics follow the
money and you will get your answers
right
so for a foreign occupation to succeed
what is required you are a foreign
occupier you let's say you are british
you have come several thousand
kilometers away from your home country
and you are trying to occupy a foreign
land
so what are the
right what do you need in order to
succeed you need arms and ammunition you
need supplies
you need logistical supply chains you
need money to bribe the locals and so on
and so forth you need all these
different tools
at your disposal
that are required in order to succeed in
a foreign land as an occupier
logistics
money weapons all of that supplies you
need a constant
stream of supplies right
the british were able to do that they
had extensive logistical routes
because they were able to conquer other
parts of the world as well
right so they have this the french did
not quite have this
napoleon tried to conquer egypt he
failed even in that because he did not
have proper supply routes and he was all
alone he was cut off from his country
the british occupiers of india were
never cut off from their country now
what happened was that there was a great
period of turbulence in the 18th and
19th centuries essentially in the early
19th century century the napoleonic wars
after which the french lost
and they became quite weak compared to
the british empire
so there was a lot of turmoil at home
there was a lot of political instability
at home
and very often there was a great deal of
neglect of the occupying forces in india
and that's why
they did not have the amount of weaponry
the amount of supplies the logistics the
money etc that they would have wanted to
have if you play and the later governor
general journal generals the french
governmental generals had those things
they may possibly have been able to
overcome the british defeat them and
india would be speaking french today
that would have happened so
at a conceptual level it's the the
success or success of a foreign
occupation depends on logistics on
supplies weapons arms ammunition
other supplies money
and all that and and also troops you
should be able to replenish your troop
supplies when you go to war
you have a battle your troops die let's
say you went with ten thousand people
and forty percent of your troops died
you left with only six thousand that's a
big problem so you need you need to keep
getting new supplies of troops from your
homeland
the british were able to put pour in
lots of troops into india the french did
not have that
luxury so these are the reasons why the
french
failed while the british succeeded
okay roll wind says why were the mongols
unable to capture japan
excellent question i may have answered
this again in the past but let me answer
again so the mongol invasions of japan
there were two invasions two attempted
invasions of japan in the second half of
the
13th century i believe
yes 13th century under kublai khan the
the emperor kublai khan was the first
the
the third emperor of the yuan dynasty of
china so the mongols had conquered all
of china smashed china taken beijing and
they had installed their emperors on the
chinese throne so kublai khan was the uh
well he was actually the first but in
his
calculations he was the third he
considered his grandfather ching is khan
the great conqueror ching is khan to be
the first emperor of the yuan dynasty
uh then um
khan was the second and ching and kublai
was the third so under kublai khan
the mongols the mongol empire the yuan
yuan empire attempted two invasions of
japan
in the late in the second half
of the 13th
century right and these were maritime
invasions they involved ships
and troops on ships marines essentially
because japan is a bunch of islands it's
an archipelago so the first invasion was
in the i think
1270s sometime like that don't don't
uh take me at my word it's somewhere
around that time the first invasion was
around that time they landed on the
island of tsushima tsushima
and they had a
bit of success the mongols
and then there was this great typhoon
this great storm that swept away all the
mongol ships and saved japan
right and there was a second invasion
six or seven or eight years less than a
decade later
and once again
there was a great
mega typhoon a great
storm that again swept away the mongol
invading fleet
so these were two acts of divine
intervention
massive storms that destroyed the
mongol invading fleet invasion fleet so
the japanese call these storms kamikaze
divine wind
so that so in one word why were the
mongols unable to capture japan kamikaze
that is the reason the divine wind saved
japan
these acts of god saved japan from the
mongol invasion
currencies would love to hear your views
about on how the geopolitical situation
of the indian subcontinent and the world
at large will evolve in the coming 30 to
50 years
well it's that's a big big
tableau you're asking to play to paint
see essentially there are three
possibilities three possible outcomes
one outcome is that we can we continue
with the status quo right now the us is
the sole superpower china is a rising
power great power almost not quite a
superpower it has big ambitions but
today the us rules the world it controls
the global supply chains it controls the
so-called rules-based global order and
so on
so one possibility one possible outcome
next 30 50 years is that the status quo
persists the americans
manage
to retain the top position in the world
they manage to retain their superpower
status and the world stays the way it is
today that's scenario one
scenario two is that the chinese win
they
they managed to
push the americans off the top position
they replace the americans there they
become they become the number one
economic power the number one military
power and they reshape the world order
in which case there will be a lot of
changes of the borders in asia they if
if the chinese succeed in defeating the
us
and displacing the us then they will
definitely want to break india up into
pieces if they become that strong they
will succeed
and they will reshape the entire
uh
global the political boundaries of the
globe and of asia the third scenario
is that india
manages somehow to get its act together
and india becomes a great power on its
own
and maybe you will have a multi-polar
world or eventually maybe india
in the next 50 years may become the top
superpower these are three possible
scenarios the first scenario is that the
americans stay on top that looks a
little unlikely right now
america is no longer producing great
leaders the last great president of the
us was ronald reagan
after that they have produced i i am
afraid i'm sorry to say but kind of
mediocre presidents
on both sides of the political divide
yeah
so the american uh nation isn't
producing great leaders anymore
it looks like a nation that it's that is
at war with itself a crumbling nation
so it is unlikely
statistically speaking
that the americans will remain on top in
the next 50 years
so scenario one is rather unlikely
scenario two is that the chinese win
that seems more likely
that the chinese will win
they have all the
all the plans in place
or they have infiltrated all the global
organizations the who the u.n the u.n
security council and all kinds of other
things and they have this extensive
network of trade supply chains they are
the manufacturing superpowers so they
have great advantages they control many
of the raw materials in the world and so
on and so forth
so it's quite possible that they make
about a dot so that is a more likely
scenario but the third scenario is that
india will come out on top in the next
50 years that is the least likely
scenario but is the scenario that i
would like to have to to come about
so how can india do that it's by getting
its acts to act together the current
political system of governance cannot
work it is extremely detrimental the
national in
the parliamentary system of governance
uh the so-called
the this this uh
supposedly democratic system of
governance
uh the federal system this western
constitution the western laws secularism
all that nonsense if in and and then the
horrible horrible bureaucracy which
slows everything down
you want to make a change it takes five
to ten years even a simple change will
take that long so and there is so much
corruption in india you can't even speak
about it
so if this continues india is relegated
to mediocrity
if india wants to succeed in the next 30
to 50 years to become a great power or a
superpower
india has to
very soon get rid of this entire system
get rid of this
foreign constitution it needs to create
a new constitution a new system of
governance democracy with indian
characteristics
india is the motherland of democracy
and
it needs to make sure that its
decision-making process is rapid in the
21st century the nations that make the
their decisions the fastest the quickest
and implement them the fastest are the
nations which will rule the world india
today has a very very slow
decision-making process
so if we change this which is a
monumental task but if we change it then
india
will certainly
succeed in becoming a superpower so
these are the things that can happen and
let's wait and watch i want india to
succeed i want india to reclaim its
rightful place its rightful historical
place in the world
rohan says the japanese company nippon
carbon is the main supplier of ceramics
ceramic matrix composites to ge
100 adaptive cycle jet engine which is
used which is planned to be used in the
us sixth generation program
the japanese have already successfully
tested the xf91 engine in 2018 with 100
kilonewtons dry thrust and 140
kilonewtons with thrust they are now
working on a 190 kilonewton variant to
use in their upcoming sixth generation
mitsubishi f3
fighter jet
how will it affect china should india go
for a deal with the japanese assistance
in kaveri program
if a deal with the rolls-royce and
saffron which are under the table fails
how will it affect china well if the
japanese are able to develop the
technology it will certainly pose a
great challenge to china because it will
it will mean that the japanese have
better fighter planes
right so this may happen in the next
five to ten years and will they be able
to build sufficient number of fighter
planes to challenge the chinese is the
question but the technology of the
japanese are developing is certainly
superior to the chinese technology
by at least an order of magnitude right
i mean a jet engine with 190 kilonewtons
thrust is amazing it's powerful you know
it's a powerful jet engine
uh the indians we in india
are developing the cavalry jet engine
it's been a very slow long process stops
and starts it was cancelled a couple of
times then it's back on the on the on
the agenda so i don't know what is the
current status it's under secrecy
there's not enough sufficient
communication maybe with good reason
uh the question is should india go for
japanese assistance in the kaveri
program
so right now what we know what i know
is that
uh we have a deal with snikma or or
safran it's now called saffron which is
a french jet engine manufacturer there
is going to be a transfer of technology
i i believe i mean that's what i heard
from
from the news
there's going to be a transfer of
technology and they're going to make
this kaveri engine work finally so i
don't know when it will happen maybe we
will not be we will not
announce it when it happens we'll do it
quietly which is good
now should india go for japanese
assistance well is the offer of is there
an offer of assistance on the table
will the japanese be willing to share
their latest technology
will they be even willing to share some
older technology with india i don't know
about that
it makes sense for a nation not to share
its best technology with anybody
right
because let's say you share it with
nation a or nation b
and what if the chinese have spies in
nation a or nation b or maybe nation c
and they are able to steal the
technology
we know for a fact that in the
early 2000s the chinese had this
extensive
uh
electronic spying program
called titan reign they had this
computer hackers who stole enormous
amounts
of uh classified american blueprints and
and military information they stole the
blueprints for the f-35 jet fighter f22
jet fighter
these uh
the cutting edge technology and they
have incorporated that into their the
chinese jet fighters which we see today
the j whatever is it i don't remember
the name
but the chinese stole that so if you if
the japanese
transfer some technology to nation a
nation b whoever it is
will they be
are they sure that these nations the
secrets will not be stolen from them but
the chinese so the japanese will have
all these worries and and and
considerations
and i'm not sure if they will be willing
to uh share their latest technology with
india so i don't i have not heard of any
such offer of assistance being on the
table from japan
so i think we should simply conclude the
deal with the french india and france
have excellent uh strategic have an
excellent strategic relationship
at multiple levels diplomatic level uh
geopolitical level
uh
and even in the military as we know the
rafal deal is there
so india has an excellent relationship
with the french and as long as we get
good technology and the recovery engine
works finally we will be able to proceed
forward from there and maybe eventually
in the next 10 years build multiple
variants of this engine with a higher
thrust maybe
so that's what we should do as long as
that deal is there we should just go for
fourth with that if the deal is no
longer on the table then we will have to
either develop the technology ourselves
or look for some other supplier
mayur says
my friend for lgbt said to me that he
wants to fight homophobia and
islamophobia when i told him about the
conditions of the lgbtq community in
islamic countries he called me a
conservative and told me that i am not
well read
how according to you can we build can we
bring today's leftist lgbtq community
under the umbrella of our civilization
and in our fight against the enemies of
the nation look the simple answer is
they need to be educated about our real
history as long as our education system
teaches
fake false distorted hindu phobic
history anti-india history of our
history of our past
people will continue to be misled it
will be very easy to mislead people as
long as this happens
right so the solution the long-term
solution is to reform india's education
system and rewrite india's history
textbooks from from a factual
perspective not from any ideological
perspective left or right it has to be
simply based on actual facts that's it
and the facts are very clear lgbtq
people have never ever ever ever been
persecuted in india in any shape or form
that's it
now
uh your friend
i mean
he says you're not well read what a joke
the other question is
all you have to do
is invite your friend
to go and move to iran or to just
spend a week in iran go on vacation in
iran and when you go there declare it
officially that i am a lgbtq person
that's it just go and do that or go to
saudi arabia
on vacation
and declare it officially in public
i am lgbtq i am a homosexual or gay or
trans or whatever it is yeah whatever
just do that
will your friend do that
because your friend should know
that in iran homosexuality is a hanging
offense
if somebody is convicted of being a
homosexual
they are hanged there's no other there's
no other punishment hanging
in other isis health territories and
other taliban territories i suppose
homosexuals are thrown off buildings
yes if you go to saudi arabia if you are
caught if you are if you are
convicted of being a homosexual you lose
your head
they chop your head off
so i don't understand what problem
certain lgbtq people have
against indian culture indian
civilization which has always protected
them and given them the same respect
that everybody else gets in india
it is a dharmic civilization which has
always treated them better than any
other culture or civilization in the
world and yet they have these uh
they have these beliefs it is not their
fault it is not their fault it is the
education system the media the
professors in colleges and universities
who are virulently anti-hindu they are
homophobic and they are spreading all
these narratives
the solution is very simple just send
one of them to china
to iran to afghanistan to saudi or to
some other
arabic or turkic or islamic country and
see what happens with them right i i
mean i'm i don't want to actually send
them there just tell them what actually
happens there to a person who is
lgbtq plus plus whatever right yeah so
that's it
that's all i can say about it it's it's
it's terrible that people are being
misled in this manner against their own
culture
the culture and civilization of their
own ancestors which has always treated
them well it's it's terrible and the
solution is very simple reform the
education system when will the
government do it
chi-ching says can you tell me more
about alisa carson can an indian
astronaut be selected for the mass
mission by nasa
okay who is alissa carson i don't know
much about this lady he's she's a young
girl 20 years old or something like that
she is someone who wants to become an
astronaut she is
an astronomy enthusiast or something i'm
not really sure why she's famous
uh
i don't know what her accomplishments
are but yeah she wants to become an uh
an astronaut she's an enthusiast of
astronomy so that's the little i can
tell you about alisa carson
uh can an indian astronaut be selected
for the mass mission by nasa
uh typically nasa does not
hire
anybody who is who is not a us citizen
for security purposes for security
reasons so the the over i mean
the overwhelming majority i would say
99.9 of their employees are us citizens
um
as far as astronauts are concerned they
do have a small
foreign astronaut program
in
under which you can apply to be an
astronaut even if you're not a u.s
citizen
so the majority of the us of the nasa
astronauts are americans
but maybe five percent or so may have
been
citizens of a foreign country so i think
indian citizens can apply to be an
astronaut in nasa the chances of success
will obviously be very slender that
applies to everybody even americans
but yes i think indians can apply under
under a certain plan under certain
program
to be astronauts with nasa
and yeah so that's the answer
okay avinash says if atoms are 99.9
percent empty
then why do we feel objects
what avinash is actually saying is if
atoms are complete almost completely
empty
why does matter occupy space
why are some things hard
why is this hard
if it is empty then why is it hard why
does it occupy space right that's what
avinash is asking so
the answer is the pauli exclusion
principle so the pauli exclusion
principle is a quantum mechanical
principle which states that two or more
identical fermions which are particles
with half integer spin
these particles two or more identical
particles fermions cannot occupy the
same quantum state within one quantum
system simultaneously
which means that they have to be far
apart and they cannot occupy the same
quantum state and the same uh
region
the same shell orbital whatever
you want to call it in an atom and so on
so what are fermions particles with half
integer spin which means they are quarks
leptons electrons protons neutrons i
mean those are composite fermions so
these are the key building blocks of
everyday ordinary matter
and because of the pauli exclusion
principle matter occupy space it doesn't
collapse into nothingness no matter
occupy space and that's why the world
has the shapes and sizes
that we observe that's why materials are
hard some materials are hard some are
not and that's why you have shape you
have size
and that is why
we feel objects
okay laksa says lakshmina says which is
bigger than the sun okay is there any
star that's bigger than the sun and what
is the name of that star that is the
question that uh lakshmi is asking
so here's the deal
sun is
a g-type main sequence star that's the
classification
it is informally classified as a yellow
dwarf star its light is yellowish mostly
white it's closer to white than yellow
but it looks yellow to us so it is
classified as a yellow dwarf
so the sun is an average size star which
means that fifty percent of stars
approximately
are smaller than the sun and
approximately fifty percent of the stars
are larger more massive than the sun
which means that on average
half the stars you see
in the sky
in the milky way
and if you have a telescope across the
universe
half of these stars are larger than the
sun
so i don't see any point in giving you
names of the stars betelgeuse is one of
those vega is another
um and and there are many more stars
like that you know you know
uh ui skew-tai enormous star and so on
and so forth so
approximately half the stars you see are
larger than our sun our sun is a
perfectly ordinary star
that's what it is
okay chirag says
was really curious about the southern
descendants of the chavda dynasty that
is choutas warrior queen abbakar rani
chauta being the most famous one it's a
very common surname in the bund shetty
community as well
should we take this to be that all
warrior communities married freely from
north to south as opposed to today where
we are forced to marry within a
specified community
i also want to know
are the chautaus really connected to the
chavdas or is it just a coincidence of
the names
matching this is a wonderful question
interesting question
so
uh yes abakka chauta was a great freedom
fighter
immensely popular queen in the 16th
century she defeated the portuguese
occupiers invaders of india multiple
times over
several decades
she is the most famous ruler and she is
a woman right so here's the thing
the chautas are
certainly a descendant of the chaudar
clan chavda dynasty of of
western india gujarat yeah
uh i think there was a migration
uh from gujarat sometime probably in the
12th century these events are kind of
not recorded properly it's kind of lost
in time
but the migration took place somewhere
around the 11th or 12th centuries and
it is known that there were multiple
waves of migration
of the chauda clan
from western india to the south of india
for instance let me share my screen
one second
let me share my screen
so you have
the chardo chardo people in goa
they are the roman catholic chapters
once again disclaimer wikipedia is not
necessarily a good source of information
i'm using it for
a convenience
so the roman catholic chatrias are
called the chardo people okay they are
gones
the etymology of this word is the roots
of this konkani word are said to lie in
the prakrit word chavda which is the
name of a dynasty of warriors which is
said to have migrated to goa from
saurashtra in the seventh or eighth
centuries
okay so this is the this is the origin
of the charlo people the roman catholic
they got converted to catholic to
christianity during the of portuguese
occupation
of western india of goa
yeah
so the charo people the go and catholic
uh the roman catholic church the
governors catholics are a descendant of
the chaudhar clan once again so that is
one interesting uh
fact that i can show you and similarly
the chautas
of southern india
right the bunt community the shatties
the chautas are also a descendant of
a migrating group of the or migrating a
bunch of families of the chavda and from
northern or from western india from
gujarat
so yes they are indeed connected to the
javadas they are the same
same
uh
extended family as the child does isn't
that strange isn't it interesting there
is also this saurashtra community
in tamil nadu i believe
which was a group of artisans etc who
migrated down south from
saurashtra in gujarat two tamil nadu
settled down over there and even today
they are called the saurashtra people
they have their own language which is
classified as a northern indian
so-called indo-aryan language right
so they are also migrants from gujarat
from saurashtra so you have had multiple
waves of migrations like this people
kept on migrating in india internally
and you had inter marriages and all i
mean today the people the saurashtra
people in tamil nadu they are they look
like tamil they speak like tamils they
have their own language but they can
speak tamil equally equally fluently
and they have almost no connection left
with with gujarat similarly the the
shakti people the chautas also may not
remember
what their origin is like and yet their
origin is in is in western india in
gujarat
so it does mean that warrior communities
and even non-warrior communities
artisans etc
migrated freely within india from place
to place as long as they were able to as
long as they
provided
value wherever they settled they were
accepted with open arms
right
and that's how it was
so you had this among the
uh in goa in in
tulunadu
right where they where the uh where
rania was the great queen and also in
tamil nadu there must be so many other
examples that we have lost that are lost
in time the thing is the entirety of
india is just one
big
gene pool
we are all the same people our genetics
bear this out that whether you're from
north east south west whatever part of
india you have the same genetics more or
less there are lots of internal
uh
local
diversities in genetics but overall it's
the same gene pool from afghanistan to
sri lanka it's the same gene pool from
balochistan even from iran all the way
to bangladesh it's the same gene pool so
that's what it is we are all
interconnected and this is a very
interesting example that you have
brought forth i'm glad somebody asked
this question
okay two questions by vishal mahajan
are the huns of the steps and the shia
new people of north china or east
eurasian step the same
and please talk about the hunik
invasions of india in detail and the
cultural and political impact they had
on the indian subcontinent are the
sketchians the suckers the same as the
huns
or are they the ancestors or descendants
of the horns
so are the homes of the steps and the
show new people of this region north
china the same so what is now north
north west china
the so-called xinjiang region of china
was never part of china it is it is it
was part of central asia
it has always been for centuries for
thousands of years a place where indian
origin people lived then you had the
turkic invasions who wiped out the
native culture
and they are the descendants of the true
of today's igors now who are the
the hodenik peoples are
the shionu the oh the ancients show new
people who are attested in chinese
sources
uh
about two and a half thousand years ago
roughly roughly give or take a couple of
centuries here and there
approximately two and a half thousand
years ago the chinese spoke about this
show new people
who are the hunnic peoples they are the
ancestors of both the turkic people
and the mongol people so the huns the
shweta hunas the hephthalites who
invaded india
uh a century a millennium and a half ago
in the fifth century a.d et cetera these
were the hons the white house they were
most likely descendants of the showanyu
they were most likely related to the
hons who invaded europe attila the hound
is a famous example
so most likely they were part of the
same
ethnic group
okay
so so the horns of the step in the show
new people are the same the horns are
the descendants of the show new people
right now the honnik invasion of india
well the question you've asked is a very
will require a very detailed answer i'm
gonna give you a briefer answer
so what was the impact cultural
political impact where the sucker is the
same as the huns no
the suckers the skittions are different
people they are in indian origin people
who ruled the entirety of central asia
up to eastern europe
uh you could say that the questions
were the easternmost branch of the of
the skittions you could use you could
you could uh classify them as that
so the heathens the suckers were indian
origin people their ancestors had
migrated out of india thousands of years
before today
and eventually they reinvaded india
about 2000 years ago
so now about the hunik invasion of india
what was the impact so
initially the hunik invasions began in
the 5th century a.d
and there were multiple waves of
invasions india's emperors resisted
the gupta dynasty the gupta empire was
in in full
was in power at the time
emperor skanda gupta who lived in who
was in power in the middle of the fifth
century he swore to defeat the hoans he
said that i will not eat on a plate and
i will not sleep on a bed as long as
these people are trying to invade my
country i will sleep on a bed and eat on
a plate
only after i defeat them until then i
will sleep on the ground and i will eat
from a from a leaf
and he kept his word and he repulsed
these invasions he was successful but
but the huns rishwater owners succeeded
in conquering parts of northwestern
india present-day afghanistan gandhar at
that time
so you had kings like kingila kingila
the first he was known as devashahi
khingira the god king hingila he was in
power in
in the 5th century
right
and mihir kula
was in power in this region in the early
6th century he is remembered as a strong
anti-buddhist king
buddhists were persecuted by him the
brahmanas were unhappy under him
all people all his subjects were
extremely unhappy against under him he
was an atheist he was not an abrahamic
he was an atheist so he persecuted
buddhists especially and even the other
people brahmins etc they were all
unhappy under his rule
but later on the hunik invasions
succeeded
and
you had huni kings who lived in india
who ruled in india the kabul shahid the
shahi dynasty in afghanistan was a hindu
dynasty these were hons who came into
india
who conquered that part of india and
they absorbed the indian culture they
became indianized completely they became
dharmic people so these were hindu
dynasties and they actually opposed the
turks the turkic islamic invasions of
india they fought vigorously
to defend india from these turkic
invasions
and again in other parts of india
northern india you had things like
various honey kings for instance the
great indian astronomer scientist
mathematician brahma gupta the great
brahma-gupta his patron
was the hunnic king of yagramukha of the
shri chapa dynasty he was most likely a
first or second generation immigrant
into india
and he was the patron of india's arts
sciences and culture so it tells you how
quickly they absorbed indian culture and
how quickly they became indian so the
number of phones who came into india
would have been very small a few
thousands maybe ten thousand twenty
thousand
maybe thirty thousand at most there is a
drop in the ocean of the indian gene
pool so today their descendants would be
alive everywhere but the
they would have just a fraction a stein
a tiny fraction of hunic blood
in them
that in them less than a person less
than 0.1 percent most likely
so that is what i can say about the
hunik invasions of india
amjad says
why did indians at the time accept and
follow gandhi i guess essentially
indians are followers not leaders see
it's like this
when you are taught the wrong values
when you when your education system
misleads you
it shapes you in a certain direction it
molds your psyche your world view
according to what they want so this is
called social engineering
right
so it's the truth is that indians
they have absorbed the wrong values
from the education system
indians unfortunately today the most
most of indians today most indians today
they regard
mediocre people as great
we have been taught we have been
programmed
to regard mediocrity as greatness
we have been programmed to regard three
feet tall people as giants
this is the conditioning that has been
brought forth
in the programming that has been
brought forth by the indian education
system and it still continues we don't
know what is leadership
recently some lady on twitter told me
that the outcome of a battle is not like
an ipl match it doesn't matter who won
or who lost
it matters who fought the best and who
showed the greatest nobility what utter
nonsense the outcome of a battle
is one win or loss and nothing else
matters you may be noble you may be
brave you may have a great personality
great character but if you do not serve
your people by winning the wars you are
a loser
so we have absorbed the wrong values
from our colonial education system the
values that we need are
there in our in our civilization
don't ask yourself what would gandhi do
ask yourself what would kali do
and there's your answer
ahinsa
ahinsa is great ahinsa is paramo dharma
but destroying a dharma is also a hinsa
destroying evil people is also inside
you are serving
serving ahimsa serving your people
whatever religion they are if you
destroy the the evil that is befalling
society the evil invaders from elsewhere
barbarians and so on so forth
what happened to india in the past two
1000 years we all know it's because our
leaders forgot the real values
and today we are programmed to regard
people like gandhi and nehru
and so on as great giants
in stature
and great epitomes are great and great
examples of leadership
so you know it's not the fault of
indians indians have a great amount of
greatness in them all indians all
religions all regions all parts of india
we are all the descendants of kings and
queens and emperors we all have the
greatness in us
but we have forgotten we have lost the
art of discovering the greatness and
putting it to use in the right direction
so yes today you are right amjad indians
are followers there are very few leaders
amongst us but i think many of you
including um many others who are
watching this channel i sense it in you
all
you are
curious
you are hungry
for the right for the real information
for the truth
i think lots of leaders are going to
come out from the people who are
watching these videos
so i am very optimistic
for the future
okay cycad says
if yamnayas were well built then why are
today's indians why do today's indians
have an average body structure than that
of european and are the omni as people
who wrote the sacred vedas ask abhijit
right good question
see
i would yeah today on average
the average indian male is about five
seven five eight tall the average indian
lady is about five four five five tall i
think i'm not sure i don't have the
exact numbers on average today
indians are shorter than europeans sure
but even today among indians you will
find exceptionally large people very
tall people very strong people indian
athletes are second to none look at
cricket whoa which country has the best
fast bowling attack in the world today
it's india
right and another sports also india is
we are beginning to see
india doing well in sports and you can
see that indians are second to none
right so why do indians today have
average body structure because of the
past
past 2 300 years in which indians were
starved systematically deliberately
year after year for three centuries by
the british
more than 100 million indians died at
the hands of the british because of
these engineered famines when you don't
get enough to eat you become smaller the
body has to compensate by expending
less energy and keeping the size smaller
so it's because of that
these dietary practices of of starvation
of very little caloric intake that
indians became smaller
now imagine
that your son
spends his whole life
riding a horse and going to battle and
all he eats is meat and dairy
and his son does the same thing he
spends his whole life on horseback
and doing war in battle and eating only
meat and dairy and let's say this
continues for five generations
even if you're an average indian five
generations down the line
your great great great great grandson is
gonna be six and a half feet tall is
gonna be muscular and it's going to look
nothing like you
it's all because of the lifestyle and
the environment
and the diet
the yamnyas did not write the rigveda
the sacred vedas they were
people who went out of india
and lived in the central asian step and
some point in time they became these
monstrous violent mega conquerors who
rampaged across europe in a very short
period of time because they were so
brutal
so so so militaristic and they were the
ultimate conquerors
so
that is the reason it's lifestyle diet
lifestyle and diet and that's it what
which which causes
um
which shapes your body structure and all
that right
and also some part of genetics indians
typically have good genetics
i think india has excellent genetics you
will find many people who are reasonably
tall or even very tall
so it's all about lifestyle and gender
and and diet and that's the answer for
you my sister my friend shaikat
okay sagar says i am a diet consultant
and health coach i have been seeing that
the west is trying to degrade our food
culture by saying that our food habits
and patterns are not healthy a few years
ago they told us that ghee causes heart
problems now they're saying it's healthy
and there's also a system in the gym
culture that to build good muscle mass
you have to eat chicken and other false
stories like that is it also part of
promoting that the west are is the best
what should we do about this
yes this is a pattern you see all the
time recently there was this about 10
years ago there was this big coverage in
in all the
in the media
that coconut oil is extremely bad for
for your heart and all that
right
i remember there is this
sri lankan chef called peter kuruwitta
excellent chef great guy he had this
program on on some tv channel
my sri lanka with peter kruvitta or
something in which he said that you know
we all sri lankans cook with coconut oil
but it's very bad for you so we'll i'll
try and keep it at a minimum that sort
of thing it's not his fault he's a great
guy but that's the kind of programming
brainwashing that the media does and
there is no evidence that it is the case
people have been eating coconut oil
consuming coconut oil in india for
thousands and thousands of years
and indians have are always very healthy
people with more traditional diets are
more healthy than people who eat the
junk food diet of the 21st century
so it's all lies
they were also saying the same thing
about ghee but now they're calling it
clarified butter no now they're saying
it's a good thing
and similarly for other things as well
they're they yeah so that's how it is so
they are trying to steal india's culture
india's knowledge by rebranding it
uh recently uh i don't know which
outlet it was they called pranayama
cardiac coherence breathing and they
claimed that cardiac coherence breathing
has lots of health benefits but they
omitted the word pranayama so they are
trying to re to steal indian culture
and rebrand it in a western and give it
a western packaging
wim hof you know is another example wim
hof is this so-called ice man
he is very famous for the wim hof method
which has made him millions of dollars
he has stolen pranayama from india
bastrika the bastika practice of
pranayam which is the wim hof method and
also living in very cold environments
taking ice cold showers and all that
which is what indian yogis have been
doing for thousands of years in the
himalayas and he has also admitted on
the joe rogan podcast that he was in
communication and contact with indian
indian
practitioners of these things
you know but he has tried to minimize
the influence from india he essentially
says it is something he came up
he came up with on his own so this is
nothing but outright cultural theft
they'll try to degrade everything that
is that is indian in origin but then
they will try to steal it and repackage
and rebrand it
so yeah that's what's happening in front
of our eyes day in and day out
and again gym culture to build good
muscle mass you need to eat chicken or
beef or or such things you don't
you can eat soy beans if you you can eat
a purely vegetarian diet and become
massively bulked
there is this armenian weightlifter
armenian strongman contestant i forgot
his name he's a massive guy he's pure
vegetarian
so you can eat soy beans you can eat
various kinds of pulses dals etc you can
eat dairy products if you are eating
that milk and paneer you can eat tofu
which is again a soy product and so on
and you have so many healthy options
plant-based options for
uh
for for your protein source so you can
build excellent muscle mass in the gym
without eating chicken without eating
beef without eating milk meat right so
these are false narratives indians need
to re discover their culture their past
and that's what is required
dungar sinchohan says is telekinesis
possible is it something that's within
the logic of science or is it beyond
so what is telekinesis telekinesis is
the ability
to control objects and move objects from
far away without touching them
so for instance i've got this these
books behind me this this thing here
if i was able to do if i were able to do
telekinesis if i had that power then i'd
be then i would be able to make these
books fly off the shelves without
touching them just with mind control
so that is telekinesis some people claim
to have this ability
it does not fall within the realm of
science there is no actual
verifiable evidence of that
right
uh and there is no
uh physical means by which you can
control things with your mind i mean any
such uh physical
mechanism has never been discovered it
doesn't mean it's not possible it may be
possible we don't understand everything
for sure there is so much that we don't
know that our
small intellect human intellect is not
able to see
uh so maybe if you are from some other
planet your intellect is 10 times
greater than a human internet then then
according to that maybe
you may be able to come up with science
science that
may perhaps
include telekinesis but for as far as we
know from the perspective of science
hard science
telekinesis is not possible in the
future it will be possible
when you have brain implants
maybe you have a brain chip with a wi-fi
connection you may be able to do all
kinds of things just by thinking
you may be able to open doors change the
temperature of something start your tv
switch off the wi-fi start the wi-fi
browse the internet all kinds of things
with just thoughts so telekinesis will
soon be possible
because of
these
implants that will be put into human
brains i'm not saying it's a good thing
but it is something that will
most likely happen
quite soon
so that's called transhumanism and so on
so forth so it
will most likely be possible in the
future
why bob krupacker says sorry
sorry for asking this many times but i
want it answered in this question yes
sir i want it answered no no no no no
so in rocheguri they found a second
skeleton belonging to the irula tribe
which doesn't have the r1a1a
haplogroup
and doesn't have r1a
okay
so my friends
have you read the one paper
the one research paper
about the rocky genetic findings
there's only one recent paper only one
it's available online i'm not opening
opening it now but that research paper
is available online
and that is the reason that research
paper is the source of all the media
coverage
so the rakery dna results
are published in one single research
paper
in that research paper
is the word irula
mentioned anywhere my dear friend
it's not
right
and
this paper also clearly mentions that
they were able to extract viable dna
from only one single skeleton
they tried extracting from multiple
skeletons but only one sample
worked
so only one skeleton has had its genes
sequenced its dna sequenced
and that is unfortunately the skeleton
of a lady
so females do not carry
y chromosomal haplogroups
they don't carry y chromosomal dna right
and that's why it can't have r1a it's
just physically impossible i mean you
can try
you can try you can spend your life
searching for that
y chromosomal dna in a female skeleton
you won't find it
right
so this research paper makes no mention
of irula
i mean the irula tribe is i think some
tribe in southern india i think
do you think it's 5 000 years old this
tribe you think this tribe was in
existence at that time
come on there's no it makes no sense
from a logical perspective my my dear
friend
so i i know that the media has been
trying to spin the iraqi dna results in
all kinds of ways
uh
there are certain outfits
media outlets like
wire
squint whatever it is i don't know i
don't remember the names
but they are trying to spin it in a way
that kind of tries to support the rn
invasion
uh migration tourism theory picnic
theory
but they are lying
because there is no mention of erulah or
a second skeleton
at all in the research paper so i hope
this answers your question
above and thank you for the question
okay missa amanda says can you shed
light on the
sun prophecy
sabdapalon prophecy of indonesia
so sabdapalon was um
the great priest and advisor of the last
hindu king of indonesia of the majapahit
v
so this guy's sab the poland was the
main advisor and the chief priest the
hindu priest
of the last
king of the majapahit empire and this
guy the king
bravoj v
he
uh converted to islam
okay
so that's what it did i think in the
late 15th century in the 1470s or 1480s
okay
so this guy converted to islam and
the the great priests of the poland said
that
uh
he cursed the king for for converting to
a foreign religion
and he said he promised
that
five centuries down the line five
centuries from that time he would return
to indonesia
and he would make indonesia a dharmic
empire a darvik dharmic country again
okay so he said that he would bring back
shiva buddha gama to indonesia which is
uh the indonesian native form of the
dharmic culture which incorporates
elements of shaivite practices as well
as buddhist practices so like i have
said a million times before hinduism and
buddhism are the same thing there is no
difference in the indonesian spectes
elements of both
but it was called
hinduism in indonesia in thailand also
you have elements of both but it's
called buddhism so there is no
you know delineation they both practice
the both these cultures practiced
a hybrid form
which contained elements of hinduism as
well as as well as buddhism
so this guy sub the poland made a
promise
that i will come back in five centuries
and i will reestablish the rule of
dharma
in indonesia so 500 years from there
it's around this time now
so that's why people are talking about
this prophecy
and recently you will you will find that
many indonesians are reverting to the
to the culture of their ancestors to
hinduism the daughter of
sukarno the former president of
indonesia recently reconverted to
hinduism
and
there is an underground movement also of
many many people coming back to hindus
many there are many high profile cases
and others as well
so maybe the prophecy may be coming true
we don't know yet but we will see
okay mansi says i am currently pursuing
a be in civil engineering i'm from
kosovo
it's okay the civil head of department
says that civil engineers should not
wait for here in bharat after our
graduation is completed we should just
leave bharath and settle elsewhere
saying there is no
nothing here in india in bharat
only if you are going to give mpsc or
upsc then you should stay in india
otherwise there is no career for you
when he himself is settled in bharat and
quite respected here when will this
problem be solved when the teachers
themselves are motivating for us to go
out of india
how will bharath benefit if most of the
hard-working intellectuals settle
elsewhere outside
i'm a temple lover since my march 2019
happy trip
i want to do something about it please
guide
okay
uh this is a big conundrum the truth is
that there are not enough career
opportunities as of today 2021
in india
there are so many new kids who are
coming out of of school college
university new graduates new degree
holders and
india is as of today not able to provide
all of them
a job
a career
befitting the level of education that
they have this is undeniable
it is also true that india needs to
expand significantly vigorously at a
very rapid rate the next 10 years 20
years india needs to grow at more than
10 percent and for that we will need the
best talent that we have
but for that to happen the government
needs to reform everything that we need
to have a significant upsurge in
manufacturing and industries and
investments into india and
and industries and all that which can
absorb engineers we need a lot more road
works and civil works which will need
civil engineers
but as of today december 2021 we don't
we don't have enough jobs to fulfill or
to to give everybody
a career
so
uh i know that your hod etc are being
negative but i would say that
there is an element of truth to it
if you want a good career
at least for some time
maybe 5-10 years
you can go abroad
get experience
get new skills
acquire the latest skills acquire
acquire
what's known as experience
acquire some wisdom
and maybe after 5-10 years
you can come back to india when you have
more experience more skills more
knowledge and you may have a lot of
money at that time maybe you can come
back to india instead of becoming an
employee you can start your own business
a startup or something
so the thing is this see when you are a
complete
newcomer when you have nothing to your
name
when you are 20 25 years old you have
almost nothing in your bank account at
that stage in your life you cannot
really contribute much to the country
but
after you reach a certain stage in your
career
maybe you are a millionaire maybe you're
a billionaire then you can really
contribute something very significant to
the country
that you love
so i would say that there is a grain of
truth in what your hod is saying i know
they are being negative
but there is a grain of truth to it
today if you stay in india you may not
be able to get the career that you
deserve as of today
so maybe
i'm not in any way trying to discourage
you i'm sure you're a brilliant person i
want you to have the best possible
career
if you want to strengthen the country
you have to first strengthen yourself
if you want to develop the country first
develop yourself invest the first 10 20
years of your career in yourself in
developing yourself and then
you will be in the right place in the
right position
to contribute significantly to the
country
so that's the advice i gave to everybody
especially new graduates etc spend the
first 10 20 years of your adult life
focusing on personal development and
career growth after that
dedicate the rest of your life to the
country
right so maybe for some time you can go
abroad and gain experience career career
experience skills all that and when you
when the time is right you can come back
and contribute to the country in a
significant manner
that's what i can say mansi
good question
uh subha says sowharao says in my
opinion phd dissertation should be
original research work
however are most of the phd
dissertations in india really original
and useful in your opinion what
percentage of the phd dissertations in
the field of mathematics and science are
really original
is it the case that the government
doesn't want to increase the budget in
research because of poor quality of
research outputs in most institutions of
the country
uh the government is certainly not
developing the education system the way
it should be education system needs lots
of reforms
it should be research oriented not
teaching oriented teaching is an
integral part but there's no real
research happening in india
so
it's not because there is poor quality
that's why they are not increasing the
budget it's because there is no reforms
and the system is following the
antiquated 19th century method that's
why there is so
there is a research output of very poor
quality so i agree with you that the
majority of phd dissertations in india
are really really bad quality
very unoriginal very poor quality there
is a website website called show the
ganga or something like that on which
you are mandated to upload your phd
dissertation phd thesis
so you can go there
and you can see the quality of the phd
dissertations phd thesis whether it's in
the sciences the humanities
most of them look like they have been
written by children
very unoriginal very poor quality there
is i have heard a lot of complaints of
plagiarism and so on
the system is rotten to the core
most of the academicians are are
what's the polite word for it they are
incompetent
most of your so-called professors in
even the best so-called institute of the
country are incompetent they are
incapable of communicating their
knowledge to anybody they're incapable
of inspiring the kids inspiring students
they are incapable of doing any original
research and that's why we are in the
shape that we are in
essentially when you become a
professor or a lecturer or a reader you
have a job for life it's just the same
system as the indian bureaucracy so all
this needs to be reformed and only then
india will grow the way it should grow
china says is
having less population a boon or a curse
imagine you have a certain amount of
land and you have too many people on the
on the piece of land will there not be
an enormous amount of competition for
all the resources for the food for the
land for for every other thing for water
for jobs
will that not be enormously long lines
for everything that is terrible that's
terrible
so overpopulation is terrible
less population is good
but
if you if the population drops below a
certain level it becomes very less and
that is also not good so
typically india had a population of
about 300 million
citizens in undivided india which
comprised pakistan bangladesh nepal sri
lanka afghanistan about 300 million so
that is a sustainable
number of people that's how india
typically was india so so today it is
like four times that that's why india is
so overcrowded
so many of india's problems
stem from this ridiculous population
increase that happened during the
nerubian years in the congress years
today we are dealing with that uh it is
not a demographic dividend it's a
demographic disaster potential
demographic disaster unless we adopt the
right policies and take the right steps
in the right measures
so less population is better as long as
it is a sustainable population
all right
so that brings me to an end of all the
questions today it is already almost two
hours i will not take any live comment
questions but thank you so much thank
you all from the bottom of my heart
for
for your viewership for the thousands of
questions you asked me every week like i
said at the beginning it is a privilege
if somebody
gives you even five seconds of attention
you are giving me hours hundreds
thousands of hours of attention thank
you so much i am enormously grateful i
am really privileged
it is a privilege and honor for me and
i'm gonna continue doing this so i will
see you tomorrow in the live chat
session i will take questions from your
live chat questions
until then thank you again and i will
see you tomorrow